[Music]
start with a circle of radius r
and then draw an inscribed regular two
end gone like this
let's figure out the area of this
regular two n gone
to do that we can decompose the polygon
into triangles
the radius of the circle is r and there
are two n copies of this triangle that
can be used to build the regular two end
gone
so the area of the regular two n gone is
2n times the area of one of these
triangles
now let's draw the inscribed regular
n-gon like this
and suppose that this n-gon has a side
length of s
then the triangle that we're interested
in has a height of length s over two and
a base of length r
therefore the area of the regular two n
gone is two n times one half times r
times s over two but this simplifies to
r over 2 times n s and n s is the
perimeter of the regular n-gon inscribed
in the circle
but this means that we have shown that
the area of the regular 2-n-gon
inscribed in a circle of radius r is
equal to r over 2 times the perimeter of
the regular n-gon inscribed in the same
circle
but that's not all we can say
because both the two n-gone and the
n-gon approach the circle as we let n go
to infinity we get the result that the
area of the circle is equal to r over 2
multiplied by the circumference of the
circle if we remember that the
circumference of the circle is 2 pi r
then we see that we've found a formula
for the area of a circle of radius r to
be pi times r squared